How bored are you?
你有多无聊？
Having nothing to do, or doing the same task again and again, can certainly be demotivating.
无所事事，或是反复做同一项任务，无疑会让人提不起劲。
And if boredom persists, you can lose your lust for life, and it can even affect your mental health.
如果无聊感持续不散，你可能会失去对生活的热情，甚至还会影响心理健康。
But does being bored have to be boring?
但无聊就一定得是乏味的吗？
A lack of stimulation can lead to boredom – this is when we start to yawn and our mind wanders.
缺乏刺激会引发无聊——这时我们会开始打哈欠，思绪也会飘忽不定。
It can happen at home or at school, but it’s at work where some experts think being chronically bored can have damaging consequences.
这种情况可能发生在家里或学校，但一些专家认为，在职场中，长期的无聊会带来破坏性的后果。
This situation has been termed ‘boreout’ and is the opposite of ‘burnout’.
这种状态被称为“职业无聊症”，是“职业倦怠症”的对立面。
Writing for BBC Worklife, Bryan Lufkin says this happens “when we are bored by our work to the point that we feel it is totally meaningless.
布莱恩·勒夫金在为BBC职场生活频道撰稿时表示，这种情况的发生是“当我们对工作感到极度无聊，以至于觉得工作完全没有意义。
Our job seems pointless, our tasks devoid of value.”
我们的工作似乎毫无价值，手头的任务也毫无价值。”
It can be caused by working in a demoralising physical environment or feeling under-challenged.
造成这种状态的原因可能是身处令人萎靡的工作环境，或是感觉工作缺乏挑战性。
Studies show depression from boreout can affect workers outside the office and lead to physical ailments from insomnia to headaches.
研究表明，由职业无聊症引发的抑郁情绪，会影响员工的日常生活，还会导致从失眠到头痛等一系列身体疾病。
But Bryan adds that “being able to identify it in us, is critical for tackling it.”
但布莱恩补充道：“能够意识到自己正处于这种状态，是解决问题的关键。”
When it becomes mind-numbing and extreme, some people joke about ‘dying of boredom’.
当无聊变得令人麻木且极端时，有些人会开玩笑说“无聊得要死”。
According to Luis Villazon, writing for the Science Focus website, boredom is just a state of mind which won’t kill you, though it can depress the immune system in some people.
路易斯·维拉松在为《科学焦点》网站撰稿时表示，无聊只是一种精神状态，并不会置人于死地，不过它可能会降低一些人的免疫力。
He says “The greatest risk from boredom stems from the things you do to combat it.
他说：“无聊带来的最大风险，源于人们为了排解无聊而做出的举动。
People who are easily bored are more likely to engage in dangerous sports [...]”, for example.
例如，容易感到无聊的人更有可能参与危险的运动……
But some experts say boredom is a natural thing and it should be seen in a more positive light.
”但一些专家认为，无聊是一种很自然的现象，我们应该从更积极的角度看待它。
If we see it as an opportunity, it could ignite our creativity.
如果我们把它视为一种机遇，它可能会激发我们的创造力。
And if our boredom is at work, it could force us to engage with mentors, career counsellors or even our bosses.
而如果这种无聊感源于工作，它可能会促使我们主动寻求导师、职业顾问甚至上司的帮助。
And Lotta Harju from EM Lyon Business School told the BBC, “boreout can mark a transition into something else: a different career entirely, or a different role in the organisation.
里昂商学院的洛塔·哈尔尤在接受BBC采访时表示：“职业无聊症可能标志着一种转变的开端：要么彻底转行，要么在公司内部换一个不同的岗位。
If people only take its cue.”
前提是如果人们愿意听从它发出的信号。”